<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infos on Academic</title>
    <link>https://chengjun.github.io/info/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infos on Academic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Cheng-Jun Wang</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheng-Jun Wang</title>
      <link>https://chengjun.github.io/info/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chengjun.github.io/info/cv/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Cheng-Jun Wang is currently an assistant research fellow in the School of Journalism and Communication, Nanjing University. He is also the director of Ogilvy Data Science Lab, Computational Communication Collaboratory. His research on computational communication appears in both SSCI and SCI indexed journals, such as Scientific Reports, PloS ONE, Physica A, Cyberpsychology, and Journal of Social and Personal Relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;contact-information&#34;&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computational Communication Collaboratory, School of Journalism and Communication, Nanjing University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Room A306, Feiyimin Building, 22 Hankou Road, Gulou District, Nanjing. China (210093).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email: wangchj04 at gmail.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ph.D, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong. Department of Media and Communication (September, 2010-November, 2014).

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dissertation: Jumping over Network Threshold: Information Diffusion on Information Sharing Websites. Supervised by Jonathan J.H. Zhu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M.A., Peking University, Beijing, China. Department of Journalism and Communication (September, 2008-June, 2010).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B.A., Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, China. Department of Journalism and Communication (September, 2006-June, 2008).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic Visiting, Australia National University,Canberra, Australia. Australian Demographic &amp;amp; Social Research Institute.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised by Robert Ackland. (February-June, 2012).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;professional-experience&#34;&gt;Professional Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director, Ogilvy Data Science Lab, Computational Communication Collaboratory, Nanjing University (January, 2015-Present).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assistant Research Fellow, School of Journalism and Communication, Nanjing University (November, 2014-Present).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Memember, Web Mining Lab, City University of Hong Kong (September, 2010-Present).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internship, Knowledge Discovery Group, Tencent Company (March-September, 2014).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;research-projects&#34;&gt;Research Projects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bringing Back the Reference Group: Agent-based Modeling of Spiral of Silence. National postdoc grant (￥50000, 2015M571722) 中国博士后科学基金面上项目（第57批), 找回失落的参考群体:对“沉默的螺旋”进行多主体建模，2015/01-&lt;sup&gt;2018&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;01&lt;/sub&gt;, 5万元，主持&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Network Threshold of the Formation and Diffusion of Public Opinion. National Social Science Fundation for Young Scholars(￥200&amp;rsquo;000, 15CXW017) 国家社会科学基金青年项目, 15CXW017, 媒体融合背景下舆论形成与扩散的网络门槛研究，2015/07-&lt;sup&gt;2018&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;, 20万元，主持&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;互联网上的集体注意力流研究，国家自然科学基金（常规面上项目），61673070，2017/01-&lt;sup&gt;2020&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;,￥655200, 参与&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;journal-articles&#34;&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; denotes corresponding author&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J., Wu, L*, Zhang, J., Janssen, M. (2016) The Collective Direction of Attention Diffusion. Scientific Reports. 6: 34059. doi:10.1038/srep34059&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wu, L., Wang, C.J.* (2016) Tracing the Attention of Moving Citizens. Scientific Reports. 6, 33103. doi: 10.1038/srep33103&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chandra, Y.*, Jiang, C.L., Wang, C.J. (2016) Mining Social Entrepreneurship Strategies Using Topic Modeling, PLOS ONE, 11(3):e0151342, doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0151342&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiang, C.L*, Yang, M, Wang, C.J. (2016) Self-Disclosure to Parents in Emerging Adulthood: Examining the Roles of Perceived Parental Responsiveness and Separation-Individuation. Journal of Social and Personal Relationships. doi: 10.&lt;sup&gt;1177&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;0265407516640603&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J., Wu, L.*(2016) The Scaling of Attention Networks. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications.448:196–204, doi: 10.1016/j.physa.2015.12.081&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J.*, Wang, P.P, Zhu, J.J.H (2013). Discussing Occupy Wall Street on Twitter: Longitudinal network analysis of equality, emotion, and stability of public discussion. Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking, 16(9): 679-685. doi:10.1089/cyber.2012.0409. [SSCI, Ranking &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;72&lt;/sub&gt; in Communication by 5-year IF].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军 (2016) 大数据计算与《纸牌屋》生成. 传媒评论. 5:63-66&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军 (2016) 计算传播学的起源、概念与应用. 编辑学刊,3:59-64.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军（2015）计算传播学:作为计算社会科学的传播学.中国网络传播研究,8:193-208.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军（2015）“今日头条”的技术逻辑：网络爬虫+矩阵筛选.传媒评论,10:34-37.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;祝建华,彭泰权,梁海,王成军,秦洁,陈鹤鑫 (2014) 计算社会科学在新闻传播研究中的应用. 科研信息化技术与应用. 5 (2), 3-13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军,刘德寰,杨旭 (2011) 从自我实现到群体互动——“人肉搜索”的动机、态度和行为研究,中国传媒报告，10(02):63-73.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军,刘德寰 (2011) 移動的時尚：追求時尚與手機互聯網的使用，香港《传媒透视》, (07):12-15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军,张昕之 (2011) “众说纷纭”抑或“一言九鼎”？——以卡扎菲官邸攻陷事件在新浪微博上的信息扩散为例，香港《传媒透视》, (09):12-13.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conference-papers&#34;&gt;Conference Papers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J. (2015). Information diffusion on Microblogs: Testing the threshold hypothesis of interpersonal effects. Conference on Complex System (CCS&amp;rsquo;15), Tempe, Arizona, USA. Sep 28-Oct 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J., Chen, H.X., Zhang, X.(2015) The Landscape of Information Diffusion on Sina Weibo: Investigating the Rich-Club Effect. Paper to be presented to the 65th Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA), San Juan, Puerto Rico, 21-25 May 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lingfei Wu, Jiang Zhang, Marco Janssen, Cheng-Jun Wang, Min Zhao (2014). Attention Balls. The 6th International Conference on Social Informatics. Barcelona, 10-13 November 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J. (2014). The Origin of Bursts in Public Attention: The Temporality Hypothesis for the Diffusion of YouTube Videos. Paper to be presented to the 64th Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA), Seattle, Washington, USA. May 22-26.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J, Chen, H.X (2013). Social selection or social influence: Network analysis of information flow within the Rich-club of Sina Weibo. Paper to be presented to the annual conference of International Association for Media and Communication Research (IAMCR), Dublin, Ireland, June 25-29.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J, Liu, J. (2013). Looking for the signposts on the web: Clickstream analysis of the flow of public attention. Paper to be presented to the 63rd Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA), London, UK, June 17-21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, P.P, Wang, C.J (2013). Rational information sharing or emotional expression in the online discussion: How does leadership spark conversations and trigger feedbacks. Paper to be presented to the 63rd Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA), London, UK, June 17-21.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J. (2012). The origin of Bursts in public attention: Peak fraction, popularity, diffusion channels, and categories of YouTube videos. Paper presented at Honours Symposium for Asian Ph.D Students in Communication Research, Seoul, Korea, Oct 27-28.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J., Wang, P.P (2012). Discussing Occupying Wall Street on Twitter: Longitudinal network analysis of equality, emotion, and stability. Paper to be presented to the 65th Annual Conference of World Association for Public Opinion Research (WAPOR), Hong Kong, June 14-16.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J., Peng, T.Q (2012). Evaluating public discussion of Occupying Wall Street on Twitter: Linking Twitter streams with search quires, opinion polls, media coverage, and stock market index. Paper to be presented to the 65th Annual Conference of World Association for Public Opinion Research (WAPOR), Hong Kong, June 14-16.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J. (2012). Jumping over the network threshold: How widespread could news diffuse on news sharing websites? Paper to be presented to the 62nd Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA), Phonix, Arizona, May 24-28.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J., Wang, P.P (2012). Does the unkown information matter for online daters. Paper to be presented to the 62nd Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA), Phonix, Arizona, May 24-28.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wu, L.F., Wang,C.J. (2011). Heterogeneity and allometric growth of human collaborative tagging behavior. Poster session presented at The 7th Chinese Conference of Complex Networks (CCCN’11), Chengdu, China, October 21-24.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J.(2011).The emergence of spiral of silence from individual behaviors: Agent-based modeling of the spiral of silence. Paper presented at The 64th Annual Conference of the World Association for Public Opinion Research (WAPOR), Amsterdam, The Netherlands, September 21-23.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J.(2011).Surfing mobile Internet motivated by fashion attentiveness: An empirical study of China mobile Internet use. Paper presented at International Telecommunications Society Asia-Pacific Regional Conference (ITS), Taibei, Taiwan, June 26-29.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;seminar-workshop-presentations&#34;&gt;Seminar/Workshop Presentations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J.(2014) Web Data Analysis. City University of Hong Kong, Department of Media and Communication. The Web Mining Workshop. 4.22-4.25&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J.(2013) The Way to Computational Communication (通往计算传播学之路). Department of Journalism and Communication, Shenzhen University. Jan 4th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wang, C.J.(2012) Jumping over Network Threshold: News Diffusion on News Sharing Website. The seminar of IR and Friends. Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation (CSIRO), Australia National University, Canberra. May 14.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;book-review-translation-and-chapters&#34;&gt;Book Review, Translation, and Chapters&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;许小可、胡海波、张伦、王成军 （2015）社交网络上的计算传播学. 北京：中国科学出版社.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王薇、王成军、王颖、刘璟 （翻译） (2013). 社会网络分析：方法与实践. 北京：机械工业出版社. [Translation of the book Social Network Analysis for Startups: Finding connections on the Social Web., by Maksim Tsvetovat &amp;amp; Alexander Kouznetsov. (2011). O’Reilly Media]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军. (2012, Aug 17). 爆发：人类行为在时间尺度上的特征. 中国科学报, 06. [Review of the book Bursts: The Hidden Pattern Behind Everything We Do., by Albert-Laszlo Barabasi].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;王成军. (2012, Jul 03). 人类 90%的行为是可以预测的. 中国图书商报, 1857.[Review of the book Bursts: The Hidden Pattern Behind Everything We Do., by Albert-Laszlo Barabasi].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;teaching&#34;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teaching interests focus on social networks and new communication technologies, communication theory, and quantitative research methods (e.g., Network analysis). I teach the following courses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Computational Communiation (计算传播学工作坊). Semester B 2014-2015, Nanjing University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Journalism (数据新闻). Semester A 2015-2016, Nanjing University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computational Communiation &amp;amp; Advertising (计算传播与广告). Semester A 2015-2016, Nanjing University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked as a TA for the following courses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COM5106 Integrated Marketing Communication. Semester B 2012-2013, City University of Hong Kong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COM3106 Media and Society. Semester A 2012-2013, City University of Hong Kong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COM2401 Fundamentals of Advertising. Semester A 2011-2012, City University of Hong Kong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COM3413 Writing for Public Relations. Semester B 2010-2011, City University of Hong Kong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional-affiliations&#34;&gt;Professional affiliations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I served as a reviewer for International Journal of Public Opinion Research (IJPOR), Computers in Human Behavior (CHB), Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology (JASIST), as well as the conference of International Communication Association (ICA). My professional affiliations include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex System Society (CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Communication Association (ICA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Association of Public Opinion Research (WAPOR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;International Telecommunications Society (ITS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;awards-and-honors&#34;&gt;Awards and Honors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best paper Award of Asian Symposium of Doctoral Students in Communication (ASDSC), City university of Hong Kong, Hong Kong (Nov, 2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best paper Award of 3rd Honours Symposium for Asian Ph.D Students in Communication Research, Yonsei university, Seoul, Korea (Oct, 2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Tuition Scholarship (RTS, Oct, 2012- Aug, 2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outstanding Academic Performance Award for Research Degree Students (OAPA, Aug, 2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel Grant from Interpersonal Communication Division of ICA 2012 (May, 2012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top 3 Conference Paper Award of 2nd Honours Symposium for Asian Ph.D Students in Communication Research, Singapore (Nov, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outstanding Paper Award of 11th China Communication conference (Jun, 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;P &amp;amp; G Award of China Market Research (Nov, 2009)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outstanding Paper Award of People.com (Oct, 2009)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top Award of the Challenge Cup of Peking University (Jun, 2009)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;programming&#34;&gt;Programming&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iching, a Python package that employs the Achillea millefolium method to practise divination of I Ching (易经的蓍草卜卦方法).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;networkdiffusion, a R package which can help simulate and visualize the network diffusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scholarNetwork, a Python package to crawl and visualize the coauthor network of Google Scholars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;visualization&#34;&gt;Visualization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News Map of China using D3.js.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Terrorism using googleVis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
